# Matthew Wigglesworth | Software Engineer

San Diego, California, United States LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/matt-wigg">linkedin.com/in/matt-wigg</a>

GitHub: github.com/matt-wigg

# Table of Contents

- About
- Skills
- Experience
- Projects
- Education

#### **About**

I am a software engineer originating from England with over five years of experience in full-stack development and digital technology leadership. I excel at taking projects from conception to deployment with a strong focus on user-centered design and scalable architecture. My current role involves leading an engineering team at Heartland Financial, Inc., where we develop customer and employee-facing applications with technologies such as Salesforce, Q2, Azure, OpenAI Services, and more.

When I'm not coding, I enjoy camping, surfing, playing video games, and watching football  $\ensuremath{\mathbb{I}}$  .

# **Active Interests**

- Estoy tratando de aprender español
- Azure AI Services & Embeddings
- Next.js 14 & Server Actions
- Web 3.0

# Skills

#### **Programming Languages**

• JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Apex/Java, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Bash, Markdown

#### Frameworks & Libraries

 React, Next.js, Node.js, Express, Flask, Jupyter, Salesforce Lightning, SFDX, Tailwind CSS

### **Databases**

• PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Solana & Tezos Ledgers

#### **Tools & Platforms**

 GitHub, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Azure, Vercel, Salesforce, Atlassian, Shopify, Adobe

#### **Development Practices**

# **Experience**

#### **HTLF**

## Software Engineer, Digital Technology Supervisor AVP

Nov 2021 - Present

Lead a dynamic engineering team to design, develop, and deploy modern, user-centric apps. Oversee the entire SDLC from research to monitoring. Champion organizational agile methodologies. Establish CI/CD pipelines and workflows. Manage project and product finances, recruitment, vendors, security, and compliance. Foster collaborative relationships with stakeholders and executives. Consult on digital trends, opportunities, and implementation best practices.

#### Frontend Engineer

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Collaborated on front-end development with Salesforce, React.js, and Azure services, ensuring robust code quality, CI/CD, and industry compliance. Developed API integrations with custom REST/SOAP endpoints and worked on Salesforce Experience sites using Salesforce Lightning.

#### Freelance Work

#### Between The Heights Productions

Freelance Software Engineer

Feb 2023

Designed a responsive and performant videographer portfolio using Next.js and Tailwind, with Vercel deployments for GitHub CI/CD.

# Hillsborough Steelstock Ltd

Freelance Software Engineer

Nov 2020 - Mar 2021

Developed a full-stack web app for national client management and Sage order tracking using React.js, MongoDB, and AWS.

#### **Additional Projects**

## **Software Engineering Applications**

Freelance

Soccer Stats (Aug 2020 - Sep 2020)

Engineered a React.js application to track international soccer team statistics.

## **Homeland Market**

E-commerce Microservice Developer

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

Developed a microservice for product reviews and ratings.

#### Wandrr

Full-Stack Developer

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

Optimized a hostel booking service's image carousel.

#### **Prior Experience**

#### **Firespares**

Director of Ecommerce Sep 2016 - Dec 2019

#### Sales & Marketing Specialist

Sep 2013 - Dec 2019

#### **SEGA Europe**

Quality Assurance Tester Feb 2011 - Oct 2011

# **Projects**

# **Professional**

- Salesforce Experience Site Support Centers: Integrated SAML 2.0 SSO with Q2 Online Banking & Salesforce Service Console
- **Human Resources Generation Application**: Leveraged Azure OpenAI Services & Next.js for HR document automation
- **Discover Subdomain Bank Websites**: Enabled targeted customer engagement through Salesforce Marketing Cloud & Vercel

#### **Personal**

- Personal Website (<u>mattwigg.com</u>): A portfolio and blog platform (in progress)
- OpenAI-Enabled Chatbot (<u>matt-gpt-chat-completions</u>): A smart chatbot using OpenAI's API
- Soccer Stats (<u>soccer-stats</u>): A platform for tracking soccer team statistics
- Homeland Market Ratings & Reviews (<a href="ratings-and-reviews">ratings-and-reviews</a>): A review and rating microservice for e-commerce

# **Education**

# **Hack Reactor**

Advanced Software Engineering Immersive Program 2020

# University of the Arts London

Foundation Degree in Communication and Graphic Design  $2008\,$  -  $2010\,$ 

# The Sheffield College

BTEC National Diploma in Art and Design 2006 - 2008

#### References

Linkedin or available upon request.